ADDY OSMANI: So today we're going to talk about Gulp 4.
好，今天我们将讨论Gulb 4
I thought I would visualize what it
我以为我会告诉你它的外观
feels like to be in the JavaScript tooling ecosystem.
在JavaScript工具生态系统中。
MATT GAUNT: I'm not going to lie,
我不会撒谎
it's not the greatest intro to Gulp 4 right now.
目前，这并不是对Gulp 4的最佳介绍。
ADDY OSMANI: What are you talking about?
你怎么说呢
There's babies here that are reminding us
我们在这里有孩子的回忆
how great it is to upgrade to Babel 6 and worry about WebPack
升级到Babel 6并担心WebPak真是太棒了
and be told that you have to rewrite your Gulpfile
它告诉您必须重写Gulp文件。
into an NPM script.
作为NPM文本。
MATT GAUNT: That sounds like Jake, yeah.
看起来像杰克，是的。
ADDY OSMANI: Although it's probably too late because Make
但是，可能为时已晚
is back in fashion.
因为Make再次流行
ADDY OSMANI: Today we're going to talk about Gulp 4.
不，不是
We've been using Gulp for a while
我们已经使用Gulp一段时间了
over in our Web Starter Kit project,
在Web Starter Kit项目上
hitting up ES 2015 in our Gulpfile.
我们在Gulp个人资料上达到了ES 2015。
And that's been fun.
很好玩
So before we talk about Gulp 4, we
在谈论Gulp 4之前，
should probably talk about Gulp 3 and some of the problems
也许我们应该谈论Gulp 3和一些问题
that Gulp 4 tries to fix.
Gulp 4试图解决
So Gulp 3 would allow you to define a dependency to a task.
Gulp 3将使您能够确定任务的可靠性。
So here we've got scripts and styles.
因此，这里有文本和方法。
And Gulp 3 would just make sure that the dependency tasks
Gulp 3将仅确保任务完成
got executed before the original task got triggered.
开始原始任务之前的可靠性。
So we've got a default task.
所以我们有一个假设的任务
We want to run our scripts and styles in parallel
我们想同时运行文本和样式
and then run the default task.
然后，我们运行默认任务。
Now those tasks themselves could also
现在，这些相同的任务也可以
have dependencies of their own.
拥有自己的信誉。
So you might want to make your scripts and styles,
您可能要创建自己的文本和样式
clean the original build directories.
清洁原始的施工指南。
You can start off on a really blank slate.
您可以在完全空白的板上开始。
Now Gulp 3 was smart enough so that if it
Gulp 3很聪明，所以如果
saw the clean was a dependency of two tasks,
发现清洁涉及两项任务的特殊规定，
it would make sure that it was only executed once.
这将确保您执行一次任务。
So all that work was only done once
因此，所有这些工作只需完成一次。
for maximum concurrency, which was kind of cool.
为了实现最大同步，这很棒。
But this approach had some problems.
但是这种方法有一些问题
Execution of that dependency set up
执行此凭证的设置
becomes a little bit mandatory once you've
一旦你成为强制
got it set up this way.
以这种方式设置它们。
It's tricky if you've got watchers or file listeners that
如果您有监视器或文件侦听器，将变得很困难
are going to be looking at one type of file,
谁将扫描一种类型的文件，
like your JavaScript for example.
以JavaScript文件为例
[? It mostly ?] made changes to that,
[？它主要是？]带来了变化
and then it just blew away all of your stylesheets
然后删除所有样式表
in your dist directory.
在您的dist目录中
It's not exactly what you want.
这不完全是您想要的。
And it can be tricky to sequentially execute tasks
连续任务可能很困难
unless you're using something like the run-sequence plug-in.
除非您使用运行顺序之类的工具。
MATT GAUNT: I think most people, whenever they have a Gulp task,
我认为大多数人每当执行Gulp任务时，
I would be surprised if anyone got away with not
他们将使用运行顺序，这是一个命令
having run-sequence in it.
令人惊讶的是，如果他们不
ADDY OSMANI: Yeah, run-sequence was sort
是的，运行顺序是
of a life saver for a while.
有点定了一段时间。
And using run-sequence looks a little bit like that.
运行顺序的使用似乎有点像这样。
But we're going to skip over it because you're here
但我们会超越它，因为您在这里
to care about Gulp 4.
突出显示Gulp 4。
So Gulp 4 drops the dependency parameter, the square brackets
因此Gulp 4降低了相关系数，并安装了方括号
syntax completely.
太好了
And it replaces them with execution functions
它们由实现功能代替
that you can use instead.
可以代替使用。
So drum roll.
打鼓吧。
Do we--
真的-
MATT GAUNT: That's what you get.
那就是你得到的。
ADDY OSMANI: We have no budget.
我们没有预算
OK, so we now have gulp.series for sequential execution
好了，我们现在有了gulp.series可以连续执行
and gulp.parallel for parallel execution.
gulp.parallel用于并行执行。
And these let you have parameters,
他们都给你系数
name the task to execute, another function to execute.
命名要执行的任务，并命名另一个要执行的任务。
So they're pretty flexible.
因此它们非常灵活。
Now if you want to go and start using Gulp 4 today,
现在，如果您想今天使用Gulp 4
you're first of all going to want
首先需要的一切
to uninstall your global Gulp 3 CLI and your local version
卸载全局版本的Gulp 3 CLI和本地版本
of Gulp, or just install Gulp 4 locally and use your NPM run
或者只是在本地安装Gulp 4，然后使用NPM管理您的脚本
scripts to run instead, if you wanted.
相反，如果您愿意。
Some people want to do that.
有些人想这样做。
Otherwise just go and install Gulp 4 CLI
否则，请安装Gulp 4 CLI
globally and locally.
全球和本地。
These instructions are correct as of the time
该指令在记录之前是完整的
that we're recording this screencast.
这集。
MATT GAUNT: Yeah, do the NPM info Gulp CLI.
是的，为Gulp VLI选择NPM信息
See if it's version 4.
并确认它是版本4。
If it is, just install it and ignore these instructions.
如果是这样，请安装它并忽略这些说明。
ADDY OSMANI: Yeah, hopefully by the time this comes out,
是的，我希望随着这一集的发行，
Gulp 4 will either be stable and the community
Gulp 4变得稳定，无法由用户取代
won't have replaced it with something totally different
完全不同的东西
and it will still be relevant.
它仍然是相关的。
But assuming that we are, taking a look at one of those lines
但是假设我们看其中的一句话
we looked at earlier.
我们早先输了
If you want to execute styles and scripts in parallel,
如果要并行实现方法和文本，
that's as simple as this.
就这么简单。
And if we wanted to rewrite some of those larger lines
如果我们重写那些较大的字体之一
that we had earlier, they'd look a little bit
我们以前有过的样子
like this, if we were going for maximum concurrency
所以，如果我们想要最大程度的同步
and replaced all of our dependency arrays
我们已经取代了所有的认可安排
with gulp.parallel.
与gulp.parallel
Dies this look good, Matt?
听起来不错吗，马特？
MATT GAUNT: Originally I said yes,
你以前说过
but I can see your next slide.
但是我看你的下一张幻灯片。
So I know it's not.
所以我觉得它看起来不好
ADDY OSMANI: No, it's not.
是的，不好。
This is in fact wrong.
这实际上是错误的。
It causes a ton of problems.
这会导致数百个问题。
So the dependency for our clean here is still hardwired in,
这里清洁过程的可靠性仍然是恒定的，
and actually gets called every time whether we
而且每次都被调用
call scripts or styles.
具有文字或样式。
Gulp 4 doesn't do a dependency check here
Gulp 4在这里不检查可靠性
because they're not really dependencies.
因为它不是真正的学分。
So your clean gets executed twice.
清洁过程进行两次。
Now to get the original execution order,
现在，要获得原始执行顺序，
we want to do clean.
我们需要清洁。
Then we want to run styles and scripts in parallel, and then
然后我们并行运行方法和文本，
our default task.
然后是我们的默认任务。
And we can achieve that using this.
我们可以使用它来完成此任务。
So here, using a combo of gulp.series and gulp.parallel,
所以在这里，结合使用gulp.series和gulp.parallel，
we can first of all make sure that each step
我们首先要确保每一步
is done concurrently and combined in a gulp.parallel.
连接完成并在gulp.parallel中分组。
And everything else can be done in a gulp.series function.
其余的可以在gulp.series函数中完成
So the execution order at default
默认启动命令保留
stays the same as before, but all the other tasks
和以前一样，但是所有任务都已使用
can be used on their own.
对方靠自己。
So you can run Gulp scripts, Gulp styles,
您可以运行Gulp脚本和方法
and not be bound on those dependencies.
您不受这些信用的约束。
It's kind of nice.
很好
MATT GAUNT: This is where I kind of come back to the point.
因此，我深入到主题
Like it's super clear what's happening with that.
但是，这很清楚。
Whereas before you could argue it's kind of by chance
在此之前，您可以声称Gulp 3的能力
that Gulp 3 is doing the right thing.
做正确的事纯属巧合
It's not explicit.
目前尚不清楚。
ADDY OSMANI: So we talked about run-sequence a little bit
所以我们讨论了run.sequence
earlier.
以前
If you want to move over from the old run-sequence
如果您想从旧版本迁移
to the gulp.series and gulp.parallel,
对于gulp.series和gulp.parallel，
here is one example of what that looks like.
这是其外观的一个示例。
We're going to skip over that because there's actually
我们将覆盖它，因为它实际上在那里
some decent blog posts out that talk about moving over
博客上有关移动的一些好帖子
to Gulp 4.
对于Gulp 4。
There is the fettblog.eu post that we cribbed some examples
有一个fettblog.eu的博客文章，我们已经复制了一些示例
for.
一个。
But these guys have actually got some really, really nice
但是这个博客的经理实际上有图表
diagrams explaining the whole execution flow in Gulp 4
非常酷，可以展示Gulp 4的完美工作方式
and comparing it to Gulp 3.
并将其与Gulp 3进行比较。
So check that out.
检查他们的工作。
There's also the We Are Wizards migrating to Gulp 4 example.
一个We Are Wizards组移至Gulp 4示例。
They include code diffs and stuff,
他们解释了刀片和其他方面的差异，
which are kind of useful and kind of nice.
这些都是有用且不错的主题
So hopefully this video was useful.
因此，我希望这一集对您有所帮助。
And if you follow their guidance, not our guidance,
听听他们，而不是我们，
because our guidance probably sucks.
因为我们的指导方针可能不好。
MATT GAUNT: Yeah, you'd be broken with our guidance.
是的，我们的准则可能会使您失去能力。
ADDY OSMANI: You'd be broken I guess.
我也这么认为
You too can be ballin' with Gulp 4.
您也可以使用Gulp 4。
MATT GAUNT: Happy baby.
快乐的孩子。